Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have an elementary level lesson about things that
我是Catherine，今天我们有一节初级课程，内容是关于
you buy for your kitchen.
你为厨房购买的东西。
That's right.
没错。
Today we are going to buy a lot of machines and devices for our kitchen.
今天我们要为厨房买很多机器和设备。
So let's jump into the dialogue.
那我们直接进入对话吧。
Let's see what we are buying and we'll be back in a bit.
看看我们要买什么，一会儿再回来。
I have been looking at this online catalog for over an hour and I still haven't finished
我已经盯着这个在线目录看了一个多小时了，还没看完
getting all the kitchen appliances that we need.
所有我们需要买的厨房电器。
What are you getting?
你在买什么？
Well, the first thing on my list is a new blender.
嗯，我清单上的第一样东西是一个新搅拌机。
I decided to also get a juicer and a new coffee maker.
我决定再买一个榨汁机和一台新咖啡机。
Don't forget to also get a new mixer.
别忘了也买一个新搅拌器。
I lent the old one to my brother and he broke it.
我把旧的借给我弟弟，他把它弄坏了。
Yeah, I know.
是啊，我知道。
I also decided to throw away the old toaster and get a new one.
我还决定把旧烤面包机扔掉，买个新的。
I am also getting a rice cooker and a steamer to make some nice steamed fish or veggies.
我还要买一个电饭煲和一个蒸锅，用来蒸鱼或蔬菜。
I'm actually thinking of completely refurnishing the kitchen and getting a new stove, oven,
我其实在想彻底翻新厨房，买一个新炉灶、烤箱、
dishwasher and trash compactor.
洗碗机和垃圾压实机。
That's a good idea.
好主意。
The kitchen will look amazing.
厨房会看起来很棒。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at some of those strange machines on Language Takeaway.
现在让我们来看看“语言小课堂”里的一些奇怪机器。
Language Takeaway.
语言小课堂。
Okay, so the kinds of machines you buy for your kitchen are called kitchen appliances.
好的，你为厨房买的这类机器叫做厨房电器。
Okay, so the word appliance, an appliance is basically a machine or device that is
好的，所以“appliance”这个词，一个电器基本上是一种用于家庭的机器或设备，对吧？
used for the home, right?
用于家庭的，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So there are many different kinds of appliances.
所以有很多不同种类的电器。
You can usually plug these in.
你通常可以插上电源。
They usually need electricity to work.
它们通常需要电才能工作。
But the ones we're talking about today are special.
但我们今天要讨论的这些很特别。
They're for the kitchen.
它们是用于厨房的。
So that's why we call them kitchen appliances.
所以我们称它们为厨房电器。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So the kitchen appliances that we are looking at or we're trying to buy is, well, the first
所以我们要看或要买的厨房电器是，第一个是搅拌机。
one we have is a blender.
第一个是搅拌机。
A blender.
搅拌机。
So a blender is a kitchen appliance that you use normally to make drinks.
所以，搅拌机是一种厨房电器，通常用来制作饮品。
So this is a glass jar that is, that's usually on the top of a little machine.
这是一个玻璃罐，通常放在一个小机器的顶部。
Now when you put in, for example, some ice and some tea and some lemonade and you can
当你放进去，比如，一些冰块、一些茶和一些柠檬水，然后你可以
mix it up and you have this special mixed drink.
把它们混合起来，就能得到这种特调饮品。
So it's called a blender.
所以它就叫搅拌机。
That's right.
没错。
So as you mentioned, it's usually used to make some sort of juice or drink.
就像你提到的，它通常用来制作某种果汁或饮品。
But we also are getting a juicer which is specifically to make juices.
但我们还买了一个榨汁机，专门用来榨果汁。
Now what is the difference between a blender and a juicer?
那么搅拌机和榨汁机有什么区别呢？
Well a blender is a machine that turns the things inside it around.
嗯，搅拌机是一种让里面的东西旋转的机器。
So it mixes them together.
所以它把它们混合在一起。
But a juicer is different because a juicer will actually take the juice from the fruit.
但榨汁机不同，因为榨汁机会真正从水果中提取果汁。
So for example, if I have an orange and I cut the orange in half, I put that half on
比如，如果我有一个橙子，把它切成两半，把那一半放在
the juicer and it turns around so that the juice will come down.
榨汁机上，它旋转起来，果汁就会流下来。
Because otherwise I have to use my hands to squeeze it and that takes time.
因为否则我得用手去挤，那很费时间。
So this is an electronic appliance that helps me get the juice from my fruits.
所以这是一种电子设备，帮我从水果中获取果汁。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So we have a juicer to make juice, a blender to make different drinks and now to make coffee
所以我们有榨汁机来做果汁，搅拌机来做各种饮品，而做咖啡的话
we have a very simple machine, a coffee maker.
我们有一个很简单的机器，咖啡机。
Okay so a coffee maker is just a simple machine that you put water and coffee into and it
好的，咖啡机就是一种简单的机器，你把水和咖啡放进去，它就会
will make the coffee for you.
自动帮你煮好咖啡。
Usually it's called a drip coffee maker because the coffee drip, drip, drip, drips down.
通常它被称为滴漏式咖啡机，因为咖啡会一滴一滴地滴下来。
But there are many different kinds of coffee makers.
但咖啡机有很多不同的种类。
Okay.
好的。
Now this next appliance can be a little bit confusing because now this one is called a
现在下一个电器可能会有点让人困惑，因为这一个叫做
mixer.
搅拌器。
So what is the difference between a blender, a juicer and now we have a mixer?
那么搅拌机、榨汁机和我们现在说的搅拌器有什么区别呢？
Well there are different kinds of mixers actually but usually the kind of mixer that we are
嗯，实际上搅拌器也有不同的种类，但通常我们说的那种
referring to, that we're talking about is one that is electronic and it looks like it
是电动的，看起来像
has these two funny spoons on the end.
末端有两个奇怪的勺子。
And when you turn the mixer on, you put it into a bowl and you mix the things in the
当你打开搅拌器时，把它放进碗里，然后搅拌碗里的东西。
bowl.
碗里的东西。
So for example, if I want to make pancakes, I put some flour and some water and some eggs
比如，如果我想做煎饼，我会把一些面粉、水和鸡蛋
into a bowl.
放进碗里。
And I could stir it with my hand, with my spoon, but it's very tiring.
我可以用手或勺子搅拌，但那会很累。
So there's a mixer that's electronic to turn those ingredients around on its own.
所以有一种电动搅拌器，可以自己转动这些食材。
That's right.
没错。
So it's quicker and obviously you don't get as tired.
这样更快，而且显然你不会那么累。
Very good.
非常好。
So I think we should take a break.
所以我觉得我们应该休息一下。
Let's go back to our dialogue.
让我们回到对话中。
Let's check out some more appliances and we'll be back to talk about the rest of them.
我们来看看更多电器，然后回来讨论剩下的部分。
I have been looking at this online catalog for over an hour and I still haven't finished
我已经盯着这个在线目录看了超过一个小时，还没看完。
getting all the kitchen appliances that we need.
把我们需要的所有厨房电器都挑出来。
What are you getting?
你在买什么？
Well, the first thing on my list is a new blender.
嗯，我清单上的第一样是一个新搅拌机。
I decided to also get a juicer and a new coffee maker.
我决定再买一个榨汁机和一台新咖啡机。
Don't forget to also get a new mixer.
别忘了也买一个新搅拌器。
I lent the old one to my brother and he broke it.
我把旧的借给我弟弟，他把它弄坏了。
Yeah, I know.
是啊，我知道。
I also decided to throw away the old toaster and get a new one.
我还决定扔掉旧烤面包机，买个新的。
I am also getting a rice cooker and a steamer to make some nice steamed fish or veggies.
我还要买一个电饭煲和一个蒸锅，用来蒸鱼或蔬菜。
I'm actually thinking of completely refurnishing the kitchen and getting a new stove, oven,
我其实在想彻底翻新厨房，买个新炉灶、烤箱、
dishwasher and trash compactor.
洗碗机和垃圾压实机。
That's a good idea.
好主意。
The kitchen will look amazing.
厨房会看起来很棒。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
Now, let's take a look at more kitchen appliances on Language Takeaway Part 2.
现在，让我们在“语言要点第二部分”中看看更多厨房电器。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Well, this first item, this first appliance is something that I know a lot of people all
嗯，这第一样东西，这个电器，我知道很多人都……
over the world are familiar with.
全世界都很熟悉。
It's called a rice cooker.
它叫电饭煲。
Now, a rice cooker, as the name says, it is used to cook rice but it does it in a very
现在，电饭煲，顾名思义，是用来煮米饭的，但它煮饭的方式非常
simple and automatic way.
简单又自动的方法。
That's right.
没错。
You put the rice in the water in the rice cooker and you turn it on to, what, 20 minutes
你把米和水放进电饭煲，然后打开开关，大概20分钟吧。
and then later, 20 minutes later, it's already cooked.
然后过了20分钟，它就已经煮好了。
It's done.
完成了。
Done.
Easy.
轻松点。
Right.
好的。
It's actually very convenient and very simple to make.
实际上，做起来非常方便，也很简单。
Now, along with a rice cooker, sometimes we also get a steamer.
现在，除了电饭煲，有时候我们还会配一个蒸锅。
Okay.
好的。
So a steamer is something that we normally use with vegetables or in Asia, a lot of times
所以蒸锅通常是我们用来蒸蔬菜的，或者在亚洲，很多时候
we use it with dumplings, these little foods that are stuffed.
我们用它来配饺子，就是那种里面包了馅的小吃。
And so, a steamer is something that you use to cook a food but with the steam from hot
所以，蒸锅就是你用来蒸食物的东西，利用热水的蒸汽来烹饪。
water.
水。
That's right.
没错。
You don't put the food in the water, you don't fry the food, but you use the steam, that
你不是把食物放进水里，也不是油炸，而是利用蒸汽，也就是
hot air, to cook the food inside.
热空气，来把食物在里面煮熟。
That's right.
没错。
So it's actually considered to be some of the, one of the healthiest ways of cooking
所以它实际上被认为是最健康的烹饪方式之一，
food because it's not as oily.
因为不那么油腻。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Now, an interesting appliance that is actually not very popular in any other place except,
现在，有一种有趣的电器，除了北美以外，其他地方其实不太常见，
I think, North America, is a trash compactor.
就是垃圾压实机。
Okay.
好的。
So, trash means garbage.
所以，trash 就是垃圾。
It's the things that you want to throw away that you won't use anymore.
就是你想扔掉、不再使用的东西。
And a compactor is something that actually takes the trash and it makes it very small.
而压实机是一种能把垃圾压得很小的东西。
Okay.
好的。
Compact means small.
Compact 意思是小的。
And so, a trash compactor is like a special garbage bin.
所以，垃圾压实机就像一个特殊的垃圾桶。
You put your garbage in it and you close it and you say, compact, and then it makes a
你把垃圾放进去，关上它，然后说“压实”，它就会发出
loud noise.
很大的噪音。
That's right.
没错。
And then when you pull it out, you open it up, the trash is very, very small.
然后当你把它拉出来，打开时，垃圾就变得非常非常小了。
Very small.
非常小。
So it's very easy to throw away.
所以很容易扔掉。
So as we said, I've never actually seen this appliance in any other country except the
就像我们说的，我其实从未在其他国家见过这种电器，除了
United States and Canada.
美国和加拿大。
I don't think I have either, but it's pretty popular in American homes because it helps
我想我也没见过，但它在美国家庭中很受欢迎，因为它有助于
save space and it's very easy to throw things away that way.
节省空间，而且这样扔东西很方便。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
You can make a little bundle of trash and it's much easier than throwing a big bag of
你可以做一小捆垃圾，这比扔一大袋垃圾容易多了。
trash away.
扔垃圾。
Exactly.
正是。
Okay.
好的。
And well, we're doing all this because we are kind of refurnishing the kitchen.
嗯，我们做这些是因为我们在重新装修厨房。
We are giving it new furniture.
我们要给它换上新家具。
That's right.
没错。
So we want to change the appearance.
所以我们想改变外观。
And to do this, we will refurnish.
为此，我们会重新布置家具。
So to furnish something means to put furniture in it to make it look nice.
所以“布置家具”就是放家具进去，让它看起来好看。
To refurnish means to change the furniture because we already have some, but we don't
“重新布置家具”就是更换家具，因为我们已经有了一些，但不喜欢。
like it.
不喜欢它。
That's right.
没错。
And so you can do this with your whole house.
所以你可以对整个房子这么做。
That's right.
没错。
So maybe you throw away the old couch and the table and the kitchen cabinets and you
所以也许你会扔掉旧沙发、桌子、厨房橱柜，然后
put a new one.
换上新的。
So you are refurnishing your home, refurnishing the kitchen.
所以你是在重新装修你的家，重新装修厨房。
That's right.
没错。
To refurnish.
重新装修。
Okay.
好的。
So a lot of great vocab here.
这里有很多很棒的词汇。
I think this is very useful for the kitchen, especially if sometimes you don't really know
我觉得这对厨房特别有用，尤其是当你有时不太清楚
what appliance you need to buy or what the instructions of a recipe say.
需要买什么电器，或者食谱的说明是什么意思。
So why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
那我们再听一遍对话，一会儿回来。
I have been looking at this online catalog for over an hour and I still haven't finished
我已经看了这个在线目录一个多小时了，还没看完
getting all the kitchen appliances that we need.
所有我们需要的厨房电器。
What are you getting?
你在买什么？
Well, the first thing on my list is a new blender.
嗯，我清单上的第一样是新的搅拌机。
I decided to also get a juicer and a new coffee maker.
我还决定买一个榨汁机和一个新的咖啡机。
Don't forget to also get a new mixer.
别忘了也买一个新的搅拌器。
I lent the old one to my brother and he broke it.
我把旧的借给我弟弟，他把它弄坏了。
Yeah, I know.
是啊，我知道。
I also decided to throw away the old toaster and get a new one.
我还决定扔掉旧烤面包机，买个新的。
I am also getting a rice cooker and a steamer to make some nice steamed fish or veggies.
我还要买一个电饭煲和一个蒸锅，用来做一些美味的蒸鱼或蔬菜。
I'm actually thinking of completely refurnishing the kitchen and getting a new stove, oven,
我其实在考虑彻底重新装修厨房，买一个新的炉灶、烤箱、
dishwasher and trash compactor.
洗碗机和垃圾压实机。
That's a good idea.
好主意。
The kitchen will look amazing.
厨房会看起来很棒。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
Now another appliance that I think is also not very popular in other countries, apart
现在另一个我认为在其他国家也不太常见的电器，除了
from the trash compactor, we saw in the dialogue a dishwasher.
垃圾压实机，我们在对话中看到了洗碗机。
A dishwasher, that's right.
洗碗机，没错。
So this is something that you find in many American homes.
这是你在许多美国家庭中能找到的东西。
So why do you think trash compactors and dishwashers are not so popular in other places?
那你为什么认为垃圾压实机和洗碗机在其他地方不那么流行？
I'm not sure.
我不确定。
It's possible it's because they're not very energy efficient.
可能是因为它们不太节能。
I'm not really sure.
我真的不确定。
I never had a trash compactor in my home in America, but we always had a dishwasher and
我在美国的家里从来没有垃圾压实机，但我们一直有洗碗机，
a dishwasher.
还有洗碗机。
This was very, very nice to have because you don't have to wash the dishes by yourself.
有这个东西非常非常好，因为你不用自己洗碗。
You put them in the machine and the machine washes them.
你把它们放进机器里，机器就会洗它们。
But you have to do some work before you put the dishes in the dishwasher, right?
但你在把盘子放进洗碗机之前得做一些准备工作，对吧？
You have to put them in the sink and water for a while and then you take them out and
你得把它们放在水槽里泡一会儿，然后拿出来，
then you put it in the dishwasher, right?
再放进洗碗机，对吧？
No, what we usually did is if there was food on the plate, we'd take the food and we'd
不，我们通常做的是，如果盘子上有食物，我们会把食物拿掉，
put it in the trash.
扔进垃圾桶。
And if it's, you know, sometimes you leave the plate for like a day or two and it's very
而且如果，你知道，有时候你把盘子放一两天，变得很
dirty, you put some water on it because otherwise it will be hard and it will never come off.
脏，你会放点水在上面，否则它会变硬，永远洗不掉。
But if it's recently used, you put all the plates, all of the cups, all of the knives
但如果是刚用过的，你把所有盘子、所有杯子、所有刀
and forks into the dishwasher and it uses hot water and some soap and it will wash those
叉放进洗碗机，它用热水和一些肥皂，大约30分钟就能洗好
dishes in about 30 minutes.
那些餐具。
So how well does it wash?
那洗得怎么样？
It washes very, very well.
洗得非常非常好。
Some work better than others, but of course, if you have food that's two days old on a
有些比其他的效果好，但当然，如果盘子上有放了两天的食物，
plate, then it won't wash very well.
那就洗不干净了。
I think it also has to do with the type of instruments that people use around the world
我觉得这也跟世界各地人们用来
to cook.
做饭的器具类型有关。
For example, big pots.
比如，大锅。
I don't think you can put pots in the dishwasher, right?
我觉得你不能把锅放进洗碗机，对吧？
No, you can't.
不，不能。
You could not put a wok in the dishwasher.
你不能把炒锅放进洗碗机。
But I think it also has to do with the fact that dishwashers are very big.
但我觉得这也跟洗碗机很大有关。
And if you have a small apartment or like me, a very small kitchen, it's impossible
如果你有一个小公寓，或者像我一样，一个很小的厨房，那就不可能
to make room for a dishwasher.
腾出空间放洗碗机。
But it seems like a very convenient thing.
但这似乎是个很方便的东西。
And of course, there are so many other kitchen appliances that, well, if we started to mention
当然，还有很多其他的厨房电器，嗯，如果我们开始列举
all of them, we would run out of time.
所有的话，时间就不够了。
But if you have any questions or any comments about this lesson or you have maybe some other
但如果你对本课有任何问题或评论，或者你有一些其他
kitchen appliances, you can come to our website EnglishPod.com and leave those there.
的厨房电器，你可以来我们的网站EnglishPod.com，把它们留在那里。
We hope to see you at EnglishPod and until next time.
我们希望在EnglishPod见到你，下次再见。
Bye.
再见。
Good.
好的。